Mobile Number: +91 9773696219 / Email Address: vishalbargode@yahoo.in

SUMMARY

I am a seasoned Enterprise Content Management (ECM) professional with over 11 years of experience in the industry. Throughout my career, I have gained extensive expertise in platforms such as AEM, Magnolia, and TeamSite LiveSite. Additionally, I possess proficient skills in Java-based Web Technologies, including a deep understanding of Spring, Spring Boot, and integration with Apache Solr & IDOL.

My passion for technology drives me to continually expand my knowledge and implement new technologies effectively. While my background primarily lies in software development, I am equally fascinated by the broader spectrum of technology.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Publicis Sapient

From: July 2023 - Till Date

Role: Senior Technology Associate L2

Content Management Tools: AEM Site 6.5

Technologies Stack: Java, JSON, Slightly

Tools: Eclipse IDE, VS Code, Git, Maven, Jira, Jenkins

Responsibilities:

- Developed and maintained AEM websites using Adobe Experience Sites version 6.5.
- Development and enhancement of AEM components based on requirements.

Accenture Pte

From: Jan 2022 - June 2023

Role: Digital Business Integration Consultant

Content Management Tools: AEM Site and Forms on version 6.5, Magnolia CMS

Technologies Stack: Java, J2EE, JSP, JSON, Slightly

Tools: Eclipse IDE, VS Code, Git, Maven, Jira, AWS, Azure

Responsibilities:

AFFIRMATION

Mobile Number: +91 9773696219 / Email Address: vishalbargode@yahoo.in

- Developed and maintained AEM websites using Adobe Experience Cloud, AEM Forms & Sites version 6.5.
- Developed and maintained Magnolia CMS websites using Magnolia 6.2.26.
- Development of Custom App, Content Type and Light Modules Deployment.
- SSO Integration with Magnolia CMS.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to ensure timely delivery of projects.
- Created custom components and templates.
- Created custom apps and rest delivery endpoints.
- Implemented enhancements and updates to AEM websites to improve user experience.
- Conducted code reviews to ensure code quality and adherence to best practices.

Trinity Consulting HRS

From: June 2021 - Dec 2021

Role: Implementation Lead

Content Management Tools: AEM 6.4 and 6.5

Technologies Stack: Java, J2EE, JSP, JSON, Slightly

Tools: Eclipse IDE, BitBucket, Maven, Jira

Responsibilities:

- CQ5/AEM Content Authoring and maintenance for test environment.
- Developing AEM components and templates, published the web content to runtime servers.

Hayagreeva Consulting Pte. Ltd. [Hayagreeva Consulting Pvt. Ltd.(India)]

From: November 2013 – June 2021

Role: Lead Consultant

Content Management Tools: AEM 6.4 and 6.5, TeamSite, LiveSite, OpenDeploy, Data Deploy, Templating, Forms Publisher

Technologies Stack: Java, J2EE, JSP, Spring, JavaScript, JQuery, XSLT, XML, JSON, Slightly

Tools: Eclipse IDE, BitBucket, Maven, Jira, Jenkins

Responsibilities:

AFFIRMATION

Mobile Number: +91 9773696219 / Email Address: vishalbargode@yahoo.in

- CQ5/AEM Content Authoring and maintenance for test environment.
- Developing AEM components and templates, published the web content to runtime servers.
- Worked on Estudio Templates, Pages, Component, Workflows, SitePublisher, OpenDeploy, LiveSite and LiveSite Content Services
- Developing and implementation of the business processes for Confidential &T customers on OpenText provided ECM (Enterprise Content Management) tool TeamSite.
- Design, develop, implement, support and maintain complex Java applications.
- Integration of Shopping products (eCommerce) API with TeamSite / AEM.
- Integration of Apache Solr with TeamSite, written Custom Java Component.
- Developed custom services and menus for TeamSite and AEM for requested functional requirement from business, for ease of use.
- Setup of new branches, content and templates for each new region in TeamSite.

Mindgate Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

From: April 2012 - October 2013

Role: Software Developer

Technologies Stack: Java, J2EE, JSP, Spring, JavaScript, JQuery, XSLT, XML, JSON

Tools: Eclipse IDE, Web logic 10.3, Oracle10g

Responsibilities:

- Developed, tested, deployed, and maintained web applications.
- Provided effective troubleshooting and remediation for web applications.
- Write JSP and Servlets to add functionality to web application based on customer requirements.
- Develop Uls with JSP, JavaScript, HTML and CSS.
- Wrote SQL queries to retrieve data from the database using JDBC.

Bhugol GIS Pvt. Ltd. [IIT Bombay]

From: June 2011 - March 2012

Role: Software Developer

AFFIRMATION

Mobile Number: +91 9773696219 / Email Address: vishalbargode@yahoo.in

Technologies Stack: Java, Swing, GML[XML]

Tools: NetBeans, MySQL

Responsibilities:

- Developed GIS based web applications.
- Use of Geo-Spatial data for analysis purpose like flooded area covered, population
- Developed Swing based application.

SKILLS

- Java/J2EE, Spring Boot 2.0, JQuery, HTML, CSS, XSLT, XML and Json
- Apache Solr, Apache Zookeeper
- Restful and SOAP API Integration with AEM and TeamSite-LiveSite.
- Beginner level knowledge of SQL, Perl and Shell Scripting

Education

- Master of Computer Applications, Sterling Institute of Management Studies, University of Mumbai
- B. Sc.IT, Mulund College of Commerce, University of Mumbai

AFFIRMATION